Email: jswalton.dev@gmail.com http://www.jwalton.me Mobile: +1-843-323-2485

Summary

full stack software developer with experience in Java Enterprise technologies, Scala, Play Framework, AngularJS, Amazon Web Services, and mobile. Always working within agile software development life cycle frameworks (SCRUM), and focused on delivering tested solutions to customer driven requirements. Strong communication skills and a desire to engage with fellow team members to collaborate and learn more. Pursuing web application, mobile application, backend, or full stack development employment opportunities that have an opportunity to work on newer technology stacks and can expand my knowledge into new areas of software development.

EDUCATION

College of Charleston

Charleston, SC

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Aug. 2007 - Dec. 2011

EXPERIENCE

Dispute Resolution Data

Charleston, SC

Jul 2016 - Present

Software Developer

- Angular JS SPA: Collaborated in the development of a client facing Angular JS application. Data powering the AngularJS single page application is provided by the implemented RESTful API. Work includes designing and implementing various modules to accommodate end user data contribution and display of data driven metrics and graphs. Data visualization tools developed using hand rolled "widget" library.
- Play Framework/Scala API: Developed RESTful API using Scala and Play Framework.
- o AWS Infrastructure: Deploying and Maintaining application code through Docker containers deployed on AWS ElasticBeanstalk. Services used include RDS, S3, SES, Lambda, and Elastic Beanstalk. Stand up Docker Image on Elastic Beanstalk for application servers and create PostgreSQL databases in Amazon RDS.
- NationBuilder Integration: Exposed a client API for accepting pushed changes/ notifications. Integrating with NationBuilder RESTful APIs in order to push new user information useful to NationBuilder CRM.

SPARC, LLC

Charleston, SC

Software Developer

Dec 2011 - Jul 2016

- o PDF Preview Functionality: Developed Servlet to have ability to serve byte range requests for PDF documents, enabling PDF Preview functionality to work.
- Letter Correspondence: Integrated external SOAP web services into letter correspondence framework.
- SOAP and REST Web Services: Developed API RESTful Web Services for consumption by JQuery front-end. Updated and integrated SOAP web services integration.
- Spring Framework: Worked to configure new modules, maintain code, and create new features within spring framework.

SPARC, LLC

Charleston, SC

Intern

Mar 2011 - Dec 2011

• Android Development: Developed an Android application to check in office visitors using third-party libraries for facial recognition

Languages

• English: Native Language

• Spanish: Working Proficiency